<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Getting Started on Ogmios</title><link>https://ktorz.github.io/cardano-ogmios/getting-started/</link><description>Recent content in Getting Started on Ogmios</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 16:33:22 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ktorz.github.io/cardano-ogmios/getting-started/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docker</title><link>https://ktorz.github.io/cardano-ogmios/getting-started/docker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ktorz.github.io/cardano-ogmios/getting-started/docker/</guid><description>🐳 The easiest way to get started is to use docker. This guide won&amp;rsquo;t cover installing docker, so make sure you have the docker daemon installed and running. Since Ogmios requires the presence of a Cardano node, we&amp;rsquo;ll be using docker-compose to orchestrate both services. A compose file is available on the Ogmios repository, get it via:
$ wget https://raw.githubusercontent.com/KtorZ/cardano-ogmios/master/docker-compose.yml -O docker-compose.yml Then, starts the components stack using:
$ docker-compose up 👆This will run and connect together:</description></item><item><title>Building</title><link>https://ktorz.github.io/cardano-ogmios/getting-started/building/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ktorz.github.io/cardano-ogmios/getting-started/building/</guid><description>You may skip this section if you&amp;rsquo;re using Docker 🐳.
Pre-requisites Ogmios is built using the great Haskell build tool stack. You&amp;rsquo;ll also need git to clone the source code, that is:
git 2.11.* stack 2.*.* Ogmios in itself is a rather small project, yet it&amp;rsquo;s using library directly from the ouroboros-network, cardano-ledger-specs and cardano-node projects. This is handy for re-using existing logic, but comes at the cost of several system dependencies that are required for building everything.</description></item><item><title>Testing</title><link>https://ktorz.github.io/cardano-ogmios/getting-started/testing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ktorz.github.io/cardano-ogmios/getting-started/testing/</guid><description> You may skip this section if you&amp;rsquo;re not interested in contributing to Ogmios.
🔧 Unit Tests First, make sure to pull and update git submodules:
$ git submodule update --init Then, simply use stack as follows:
$ stack test ogmios:unit 💨 Smoke Tests Run the whole components stack using docker-compose as follows:
$ docker-compose up To tear down, press CTRL+C and then run:
$ docker-compose down</description></item><item><title>JSON-WSP</title><link>https://ktorz.github.io/cardano-ogmios/getting-started/json-wsp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ktorz.github.io/cardano-ogmios/getting-started/json-wsp/</guid><description>Overview Ogmios' interface is built on top of JSON-WSP which is a tiny standard to give some structure to the various messages that can be exchanged with Ogmios. The standard specifies a top-level JSON envelope by which messages must abide, as well as a semantic for some of the fields. In particular, there are 4 types of messages possible in JSON-WSP:
descriptions requests responses faults (which are a special kind of responses).</description></item></channel></rss>